Over the past six months, I've spent my time
خلال الست أشهر الماضية، قضيت وقتي
traveling. I think I've done 60,000 miles,
اسافر. اعتقد انني قطعت 60 ألف ميلا
but without leaving my desk.
لكن دون أن أغادر مكتبي.
And the reason I can do that is because I'm actually two people.
والسبب وراء مقدرتي على فعل ذلك هو أنني في الحقيقة شخصين.
I look like one person but I'm two people. I'm Eddie who is here,
أبدو كشخص واحد لكني شخصين. انا إيدي الذي أمامكم
and at the same time, my alter ego is a big green boxy
وفي نفس الوقت، فإن شخصيتي الاخرى هي كصندوق كبير اخضر
avatar nicknamed Cyber Frank.
مُجسّد يسمى سايبر فرانك.
So that's what I spend my time doing. I'd like to start,
إذاً هذا ما أقضي وقتي عليه. أرغب بالبدء
if it's possible, with a test, because I do business stuff,
اذا كان ذلك ممكنًا، باختبار، لأنني أقوم بمهام في مجال الأعمال،
so it's important that we focus on outcomes.
لذا فإنه من المهم أن نركّز على النتائج.
And then I struggled, because I was thinking to myself,
ومن ثم دخلت في صراع، لأنني كنت أفكر بنفسي
"What should I talk? What should I do? It's a TED audience.
"ماذا يتوجب علي أن أقول؟ ماذا أفعل؟ إنهم جمهور TED
It's got to be stretching. How am I going to make — ?"
يجب ان ابذل قصارى جهدي. كيف يمكنني التحضير؟"
So I just hope I've got the level of difficulty right.
لذا آمل أن أكون قد فهمت مستوى الصعوبة بشكل صحيح.
So let's just walk our way through this.
لذلك دعونا نشق طريقنا من خلال هذا.
Please could you work this through with me? You can shout out the answer if you like.
هل يمكنكم رجاءً ان تمشوا معي؟ يمكنكم الصدح بالاجابة اذا شئتم.
The question is, which of these horizontal lines is longer?
السؤال هو، أي هذه الخطوط الأفقية أطول؟
The answer is?
الاجابة هي؟
Audience: The same.Eddie Obeng: The same.
الجمهور: نفس الطول. إيدي أوبنغ: نفس الطول.
No, they're not the same. (Laughter)
لا. ليسوا نفس الطول. (ضحك)
They're not the same. The top one is 10 percent longer than the bottom one.
ليسوا نفس الطول. الخط الأعلى أطول بـ 10% من ذاك الموجود في الأسفل.
So why did you tell me they were the same? Do you remember when we were kids at school,
إذاً لم تقولون أنهم نفس الطول؟ هل تذكرون حينما كنا أطفالًا في المدرسة،
about that big, they played the same trick on us?
بهذا الحجم تقريبًا، خدعونا باستخدام نفس اللغز؟
It was to teach us parallax. Do you remember?
كان الهدف منه تعليمنا إختلاف المنظر. هل تذكرون؟
And you got, you said, "It's the same!" And you got it wrong.
ونميل للقول، "أنهما من نفس الطول!" ونخطئ في ذلك.
You remember? And you learned the answer, and you've carried this answer in your head for 10, 20, 30, 40 years:
هل تذكرون؟ وقد تعلمنا الاجابة، ونحملها في رؤوسنا لمدة 10 أو 20 أو 30 أو 40 عاما
The answer is the same. The answer is the same. So when you're asked what the lengths are,
الاجابة هي الطول نفسه. لذا فعندما نُسأل عن الأطوال،
you say they're the same, but they're not the same, because I've changed it.
نقول نفس الطول، لكنهم ليسوا نفس الطول، لأنني قمت بتغييرها.
And this is what I'm trying to explain has happened to us in the 21st century.
وهذا ما أريد أن أشرحه هو ما حدث لنا في القرن الحادي والعشرين.
Somebody or something has changed the rules
شخص ما أو شيئ ما قد غيّر القواعد
about how our world works.
حول الكيفية التي يعمل بها العالم.
When I'm joking, I try and explain it happened at midnight,
عندما أمزح، أحاول وأشرح ان هذا قد حدث منتصف الليل،
you see, while we were asleep, but it was midnight 15 years ago. Okay?
بينما كنا نائمين، لكنه قد حدث منتصف الليل قبل 15 عاماً مضت. حسناً؟
You didn't notice it? But basically, what they do is,
لم تلاحظوها؟ لكن ما يفعلونه في الأساس هو،
they switched all the rules round, so that the way to
قلب كل الموازين، بحيث أصبح الطريق
successfully run a business, an organization, or even a country,
للنجاح في ادارة عمل تجاري، مؤسسة أو حتى دولة،
has been deleted, flipped, and it's a completely new
محذوفًا، قُلب، واصبح جديدًا كُليـًا
— you think I'm joking, don't you — there's a completely new set of rules in operation. (Laughter)
-- تعتقدون أنني أمزح، أليس كذلك --هنالك قواعد جديدة للعبة. (ضحك)
Did you notice that? I mean, you missed this one.
هل لاحظتم ذلك؟ أعني، لقد فاتتكم هذه النقطة.
You probably — No, you didn't. Okay. (Laughter)
ربما أنتم -- لا، لم تفتكم. حسناً. (ضحك)
My simple idea is that what's happened is,
فكرتي البسيطة هي أن ما حدث هو،
the real 21st century around us isn't so obvious to us,
أن القرن الـ 21 الحقيقي حولنا ليس واضحًا لنا،
so instead we spend our time responding rationally
لذا عوضاً عن قضاء وقتنا بالاستجابة المنطقية
to a world which we understand and recognize,
لعالم نفهمه ونعرفه،
but which no longer exists.
لكنه لم يعد موجوداً.
You don't believe me, do you? Okay. (Applause)
أنتم لا تصدقونني، أليس كذلك؟. حسناً. (تصفيق)
So let me take you on a little journey of many of the things I don't understand.
دعوني آخذكم في جولة صغيرة لعدة اشياء لا أفهمها
If you search Amazon for the word "creativity,"
اذا بحثتم في موقع أمازون عن كلمة "إبداع،"
you'll discover something like 90,000 books.
ستكتشفون حوالي 90 ألف كتاب.
If you go on Google and you look for "innovation + creativity,"
اذا بحثتم في موقع جوجل عن "الابتكار والابداع،"
you get 30 million hits. If you add the word "consultants," it doubles to 60 million. (Laughter)
سوف تحصل على 30 مليون نتيجة بحث. اذا اضفتم الكلمة "مستشارون"، فالعدد يتضاعف الى 60 مليون. (ضحك)
Are you with me? And yet, statistically, what you discover
هل تتابعونني؟ ولكن ما نكتشفه إحصائياً
is that about one in 100,000 ideas is found making money
هو أن واحدة من كل 100 ألف فكرة تجني الأموال
or delivering benefits two years after its inception.
أو تعود بالأرباح بعد عامين من بدايتها.
It makes no sense. Companies make their expensive executives
هذا ليس منطقيا. تجعل الشركات موظفيها التنفيذيين
spend ages carefully preparing forecasts and budgets
يقضون سنوات طوال في التحضير بعناية للتوقعات والميزانيات
which are obsolete or need changing before they can be published.
التي عفا عليها الزمن أو بحاجة لتغيير قبل أن تُنشر.
How is that possible? If you look at the visions we have,
كيف يمكن ذلك؟ اذا نظرت الى الرؤى التي لدينا
the visions of how we're going to change the world,
الرؤى للكيفية التي سنقوم بتغيير العالم من خلالها،
the key thing is implementation. We have the vision.
فالشيء الرئيسي هو التنفيذ. لدينا الرؤية.
We've got to make it happen.
ينبغي علينا تنفيذها.
We've spent decades professionalizing implementation.
لقد قضينا عقودا من الزمان نحترف التنفيذ.
People are supposed to be good at making stuff happen.
يُفترض أن الناس أصبحوا جيدين في تنفيذ الخطط.
However, if I use as an example a family of five
لكن، اذا استخدمت مثالا لعائلة من خمس افراد
going on holiday, if you can imagine this,
يذهبون لقضاء العطلة، لو تخيلتم ذلك،
all the way from London all the way across to Hong Kong,
طوال الطريق من لندن الى هونغ كونغ،
what I want you to think about is their budget is only 3,000 pounds of expenses.
ما أريدكم أن تفكروا به هو ميزانيتهم البالغة 3000 جنيه فقط.
What actually happens is, if I compare this to the average
ما يحدث حقيقة هو، اذا قارنت هذا مع متوسط
real project, average real successful project,
مشروع حقيقي، متوسط مشروع حقيقي ناجح،
the family actually end up in Makassar, South Sulawesi,
فان الأسرة سينتهي بها الحال في ماكاسار، جنوب سولاوسي،
at a cost of 4,000 pounds,
بتكلفة 4000 جنيه،
whilst leaving two of the children behind. (Laughter)
تاركين الأطفال خلفهم. (ضحك)
What I'm trying to explain to you is, there are things which don't make sense to us.
ما أحاول شرحه هو، هناك أشياء غير منطقية بالنسبة لنا.
It gets even worse than that. Let me just walk you through this one.
والأمر يزداد سوءا أكثر من ذلك. سأخذكم معي عبر هذا المثال.
This is a quote, and I'll just pick words out of it.
هذا إقتباس، وسأقوم باختيار الكلمات منه.
It says -- I'll put on the voice -- "In summary, your Majesty,
يقول -- سأقرؤها -- " في الخلاصة، جلالتك،
the failure to foresee the timing, extent and severity
الفشل في توقع الزمن، يمتد وشدة
of the crisis was due to the lack of creativity
الأزمة كانت نتيجة لنقص الابداع
and the number of bright minds," or something like that.
وعدد العقول الذكية،" أو شيئ مثل ذاك.
This was a group of eminent economists apologizing to the Queen of England
كانت هذه مجموعة من الاقتصاديين البارزين يعتذرون لملكة انجلترا
when she asked the question,
عندما سألت السؤال،
"Why did no one tell us that the crisis was coming?" (Laughter)
" لماذا لم يخبرنا أحد بأن هناك أزمة قادمة؟" (ضحك)
I'll never get my knighthood. I'll never get my knighthood. (Laughter)
لن أحصل على لقب فارس من الملكة. لن أحصل على لقب فارس من الملكة. (ضحك)
That's not the important point. The thing you have to remember is,
تلك ليست نقطة مهمة. الشيئ الذي ينبغي عليكم تذكره هو،
these are eminent economists, some of the smartest people
هؤلاء اقتصاديون بارزون، ثلة من أذكى الناس
on the planet. Do you see the challenge? (Laughter)
على كوكب الأرض. هل ترون التحدي؟ (ضحك)
It's scary. My friend and mentor, Tim Brown of IDEO,
انه مخيف. صديقي ومرشدي، تيم براون من IDEO
he explains that design must get big, and he's right.
يشرح أن التصميم ينبغي أن يكبر، وهو صائب في ذلك.
He wisely explains this to us. He says design thinking
فهو يشرح ذلك بحكمة لنا. يقول ان تفكير التصميم
must tackle big systems for the challenges we have.
ينبغي أن يتعامل مع الانظمة الكبيرة لأجل التحديات التي لدينا.
He's absolutely right.
وهو محق تماماً.
And then I ask myself, "Why was it ever small?"
ثم أسأل نفسي، " لماذا كان التصميم صغيراً في الأصل؟"
Isn't it weird? You know, if collaboration is so cool,
أليس هذا غريباً؟ اذا كان التعاون أمر جيد،
is cross-functional working is so amazing,
وتقاطع المهام الوظيفية مدهش للغاية،
why did we build these huge hierarchies? What's going on?
لماذا نقوم ببناء هذه الهياكل الضخمة؟ مالذي يجري؟
You see, I think what's happened, perhaps, is that
كما ترون، أعتقد ان ما يحدث، ربما أننا
we've not noticed that change I described earlier.
لم نلحظ ذلك التغيير الذي ذكرته مسبقاً.
What we do know is that the world has accelerated.
الذي نعلمه هو أن العالم قد تسارع.
Cyberspace moves everything at the speed of light.
يحرّك فضاء الانترنت كل شيء بسرعة الضوء.
Technology accelerates things exponentially.
تُسارع التقانة الأشياء بصورة أُسيّة.
So if this is now, and that's the past,
إذاً هذا الذي يجري الآن وذلك الماضي،
and we start thinking about change, you know,
ونبدأ بالتفكير حول التغيير، كما تعلمون،
all governments are seeking change, you're here seeking change,
كل الحكومات ترغب بالتغيير، أنتم هنا ترغبون بالتغيير،
everybody's after change, it's really cool. (Laughter)
كل شخص يسعى وراء التغيير، هذا جميل حقاً. (ضحك)
So what happens is, we get this wonderful whooshing acceleration and change.
إذاً الذي حدث هو، اننا نحصل على هذا التسارع الرنان والتغيير الرائع.
The speed is accelerating. That's not the only thing.
السرعة تتزايد. هذا ليس الشيئ الوحيد.
At the same time, as we've done that, we've done something really weird.
في نفس الوقت، بينما أنتهينا من ذلك، قمنا بعمل شيئ غريب حقاً.
We've doubled the population in 40 years,
لقد ضاعفنا عدد السكان خلال 40 سنة،
put half of them in cities, then connected them all up so they can interact.
وضعنا نصفهم في المدن، ثم وصلّناهم وشبّكناهم بحيث يستطيعون التفاعل.
The density of the interaction of human beings is amazing.
كثافة التفاعل بين البشر شيء مدهش للغاية.
There are charts which show all these movements of information. That density of information is amazing.
هناك رسوم بيانية تظهر حركة المعلومات. تلك الكثافة المعلوماتية مدهشة.
And then we've done a third thing.
ثم قمنا بفعل شيء ثالث.
you know, for those of you who have as an office
كما تعلمون، لأؤلئك الذين لديهم مكتب
a little desk underneath the stairs, and you say, well this is my little desk under the stairs,
هناك مكتب صغير تحت الدرج، وتقول، حسناً ها هو مكتبي الصغير تحت الدرج،
no! You are sitting at the headquarters of a global corporation if you're connected to the Internet.
لا! أنت تجلس في المبنى الرئيسي للتعاون الدولي اذا كنت متصلًا بالانترنت.
What's happened is, we've changed the scale.
الذي حدث هو، لقد قمنا بتغيير المقياس.
Size and scale are no longer the same.
الحجم والمقياس لم يعودا الشيء ذاته.
And then add to that, every time you tweet,
ثم تضيف لذلك، كل وقت تكتب تغريدة،
over a third of your followers follow from a country
أكثر من ثلث متبعيك من دولة
which is not your own.
لست من أهلها.
Global is the new scale. We know that.
العالم هو المقياس الجديد. نحن نعرف ذلك.
And so people say things like, "The world is now a turbulent place." Have you heard them saying things like that?
لذا يقول الناس أشياء مثل، " العالم الآن مكان مضطرب." هل سمعتهم يقولون أشياء كتلك؟
And they use it as a metaphor. Have you come across this?
ويستخدمونها كمجاز. هل مررتم بهذا الشيء؟
And they think it's a metaphor, but this is not a metaphor.
ويعتبرونها مجازاً، لكنها ليست كذلك.
It's reality. As a young engineering student, I remember
إنها الحقيقة. كطالب هندسة يافع، أذكر
going to a demonstration where they basically,
ذهابي لأحد التقديمات حيث،
the demonstrator did something quite intriguing.
قام أحد المقدمين بشيء مثير للفضول.
What he did was, he got a transparent pipe — have you seen this demonstration before? —
ما فعله هو أنه احضر أنبوبًا شفّافًا -- هل رأيتم هذه التجربة من قبل؟ --
he attached it to a tap. So effectively what you had was,
علقه بصنبور. وما تحصل عليه،
you had a situation where — I'll try and draw the tap
كان في وضعية حيث – سأحاول رسم الصنبور
and the pipe, actually I'll skip the tap. The taps are hard.
والأنبوب، والواقع أنني سوف أتخطى الصنبور. الصنابير صعبة.
Okay? So I'll write the word "tap." Is that okay? It's a tap. (Laughter)
حسنا؟ سوف اكتب كلمة "صنبور." هل اتفقنا ؟ إنه صنبور. (ضحك)
Okay, so he attaches it to a transparent pipe, and he turns the water on.
حسنا، إذا فقد قام بوصله بأنبوب شفاف، وقام بفتح صنبور الماء .
And he says, do you notice anything? And the water is whooshing down this pipe.
وقال، هل لاحظتم أي شيء؟ والماء يسري في الأنابيب.
I mean, this is not exciting stuff. Are you with me?
أعني، هذا الأمر ليس مثيرًا. هل أنتم معي؟
So the water goes up. He turns it back down. Great.
إذا الماء ارتفع. فغلق الصنبور. رائع.
And he says, "Anything you notice?" No. Then he sticks a needle into the pipe,
ويقول: "هل لاحظتم شيئا؟" لا. لاحقا غرز ابرة داخل الأنبوب،
and he connects this to a container, and he fills
وربط هذا بوعاء، وملأ
the container up with green ink. You with me?
الوعاء بحبر أخضر. أأنتم معي؟
So guess what happens? A thin green line comes out
إذا خمنوا ما حصل؟ خط أخضر رقيق يخرج
as it flows down the pipe. It's not that interesting.
متدفقًا من الأنبوب.ذلك ليس مثيرًا للإهتمام.
And then he turns the water up a bit, so it starts coming back in. And nothing changes.
وقام بعد ذلك بتشغيل صنبور الماء لوهلة، لذا عاود الكرّة ولم يتغير شيء.
So he's changing the flow of the water, but it's just a boring green line.
حيث أنه قام بتغيير تدفق المياه، ولكنّه مجرد خطٍ أخضر ممل.
He adds some more. He adds some more. And then something weird happens.
ويضيف أكثر. ويضيف المزيد. ومن ثم حدث شيء غريب.
There's this little flicker, and then as he turns it ever so slightly more,
هناك وميض خافت ، وبعد ذلك وبينما يزيد من التدفق قليلاً،
the whole of that green line disappears, and instead
اختفي الخط الأخضر بأسره، وبدلاً منه
there are these little sort of inky dust devils close to the needle.
تواجد غبار على شكل حبر على مقربة من الإبرة.
They're called eddies. Not me. And they're violently dispersing the ink
انها تدعى بالدوامات. لست أنا. وهي تنثر الحبر بعنف
so that it actually gets diluted out, and the color's gone.
حيث انه قد تحول الى محلول مخفف، عديم اللون.
What's happened in this world of pipe
ما الذي حدث في هذا الأنبوب
is somebody has flipped it. They've changed the rules from laminar to turbulent.
هل قام شخص بقلبه؟ لقد غيروا القواعد من مستوية الى مضطربة.
All the rules are gone. In that environment, instantly,
وجميع القواعد اندثرت. في هذه البيئة، وعلى الفور،
all the possibilities which turbulence brings are available,
فإن جميع الاحتمالات المضطربة موجودة،
and it's not the same as laminar.
وهي ليست كتلك المستوية.
And if we didn't have that green ink, you'd never notice.
وإذا لم يكن لدينا هذا الحبر الأخضر، فإننا لن نلاحظ ابدا.
And I think this is our challenge, because somebody
وأعتقد أن هذا هو التحدي الذي نواجهه، لأن شخصا ما
has actually increased — and it's probably you guys with all your tech and stuff —
زاد في الواقع – وعلى الأرجح أنتم يا رفاق مع كل هذه التقانة والأمور –
the speed, the scale and the density of interaction.
السرعة والحجم وكثافة التفاعل.
Now how do we cope and deal with that?
الآن كيف نتعاون ونتعامل مع ذلك؟
Well, we could just call it turbulence, or we could try and learn.
حسنا، يمكننا أن نكتفي ونطلق عليه إضطرابًا، أو يمكننا أن نحاول ونتعلم.
Yes, learn, but I know you guys grew up in the days when
نعم، التعلم، ولكن أنا أعلم يا رفاق أنكم نشأتم في أيام حيث
there were actually these things called correct answers,
كانت هذه الأشياء تسمى الإجابات الصحيحة،
because of the answer you gave me to the horizontal line puzzle,
بسبب الجواب الذي أعطيتموه لي لأحجية الخطوط الأفقية،
and you believe it will last forever.
وكنتم تعتقدون أنها سوف تستمر إلى الأبد.
So I'll put a little line up here which represents learning,
لذا سوف أرسم خطا صغيرا هنا يمثل التعلم،
and that's how we used to do it. We could see things,
وهذا كيف إعتدنا القيام بها. يمكننا أن نرى الأشياء،
understand them, take the time to put them into practice.
ونفهمها، وأخذ الوقت لوضعها موضع التنفيذ.
Out here is the world. Now, what's happened to our pace
هنا هو العالم. والآن، ما الذي حدث لخطانا
of learning as the world has accelerated? Well, if you work
في التعلم في ظل تسارع العالم؟ حسنا، إذا كنت تعمل
for a corporation, you'll discover it's quite difficult to work
لحساب شركة، فسوف نكتشف أنه من الصعب جداً العمل
on stuff which your boss doesn't approve of, isn't in the strategy,
في الأمور التي لا يوافق عليها رئيسك، ليست في الاستراتيجية،
and anyway, you've got to go through your monthly meetings.
وعلى أية حال، فإنه يتوجب عليك الذهاب للاجتماعات الشهرية.
If you work in an institution, one day you will get them to make that decision.
إذا كنت تعمل في مؤسسة، فإنك في يوم ما ستجعلهم يتخذون ذلك القرار.
And if you work in a market where people believe in cycles,
وإذا كنت تعمل في السوق حيث يؤمن الناس بالدورات،
it's even funnier, because you have to wait all the way
فإنها مسلية أكثر، لأنه عليك الانتظار طوال
for the cycle to fail before you go, "There's something wrong." You with me?
الدورة لتفشل قبل أن تنطلق، "هناك شيء خاطئ". هل أنتم معي؟
So it's likely that the line, in terms of learning, is pretty flat.
لذا فمن المرجح أن الخط، من ناحية التعلم، مستوٍ نوعا ما.
You with me? This point over here, the point at which
هل أنتم معي؟ هذه النقطة هنا ، النقطة التي
the lines cross over, the pace of change
تقطعها الخطوط , هي وتيرة التغيير
overtakes the pace of learning,
وهي تتفوق على وتيرة التعلم،
and for me, that is what I was describing
و بالنسبة لي، هذا ما كنت أعنيه
when I was telling you about midnight.
عندما قلت لكم في حوالي منتصف الليل.
So what does it do to us? Well, it completely transforms what we have to do,
لذا ماذا تفعل لنا؟ حسنا، إنها تُحوّل تماما ما يتوجب علينا القيام به،
many mistakes we make. We solve last year's problems
العديد من الأخطاء التي نتخذها. نحل مشاكل العام الماضي
without thinking about the future. If you try and think about it,
دون التفكير في المستقبل. إذا حاولت وفكرت في الأمر،
the things you're solving now, what problems are they going to bring in the future?
الأمور التي تحلها الآن، ماهي المشاكل التي سوف تجلبها لنا في المستقبل؟
If you haven't understood the world you're living in,
إذا كنت لم تكن تفهم العالم الذي تعيش فيه،
it's almost impossible to be absolutely certain that what you're going to deliver fits.
يكاد يكون من المستحيل أن تكون على يقين تام أن ما أنت بصدد تسليمه يتلائم.
I'll give you an example, a quick one. Creativity and ideas,
سوف أعطيكم بسرعة مثالا واحدا ، الإبداع والأفكار،
I mentioned that earlier. All the CEOs around me, my clients, they want innovation,
ذكرت ذلك سابقا. جميع الرؤساء التنفيذيين حولي، زبائني، يريدون الابتكار،
so they seek innovation. They say to people, "Take risks and be creative!"
لذا فهم يبحثون عن الابتكار. أنهم يقولون للناس، "تحملوا المخاطر وكونوا مبدعين!"
But unfortunately the words get transformed as they travel through the air.
ولكن للأسف الكلمات تتغير عندما تنتقل في الهواء.
Entering their ears, what they hear is, "Do crazy things and then I'll fire you." Why? (Laughter) Because —
في الحقيقة، ما يسمعون هو، "قم بأشياء مجنونة ومن ثم سوف أطردك من العمل". لماذا؟ (ضحك) لأن –
Why? Because in the old world, okay, in the old world,
لماذا؟ لأن في العالم القديم، حسنا، في العالم القديم،
over here, getting stuff wrong was unacceptable.
هنا، الحصول على الأشياء الغير جيدة أمر غير مقبول.
If you got something wrong, you'd failed. How should you be treated?
إذا كنت حصلت على شيء خاطئ، فإنك قد فشلت. كيف سيتم التعامل معك؟
Well, harshly, because you could have asked somebody who had experience.
حسنا، بقسوة، لأنه كان بمقدورك أن تسئل شخصًا ذي خبرة.
So we learned the answer and we carried this in our heads for 20, 30 years, are you with me?
اذا فقد تعلمنا الإجابة، وقمنا بحفظ ذلك في رؤوسنا لـ 20، 30 عاماً، هل أنتم معي؟
The answer is, don't do things which are different.
الجواب، لا تقم بأمور مختلفة.
And then suddenly we tell them to and it doesn't work.
وفجأة اخبرناهم بذلك ولم تنجح.
You see, in reality, there are two ways you can fail in our new world.
هل رأيت، في الواقع، هناك طريقتان يمكنك الفشل من خلالها في عالمنا الجديد.
One, you're doing something that you should follow a procedure to, and it's a very difficult thing,
الأولى، أن تفعل شيئا يتوجب عليك اتباع إجراءات فيه، و هو شيء صعب جداً،
you're sloppy, you get it wrong. How should you be treated? You should probably be fired.
فأنت مهمل، فهمتها خطأً. كيف يجب أن تُعامل؟ ربما ينبغي أن أطردك من العمل.
On the other hand, you're doing something new, no one's ever done before,
من ناحية أخرى، فلقد كنت تفعل شيئا جديداً، لم يقم أحد به سابقا،
you get it completely wrong. How should you be treated?
لكنك فهمته بشكل خاطئٍ تماما. كيف يجب أن تُعامل؟
Well, free pizzas! You should be treated better than the people who succeed.
حسنا، بيتزا مجانية ! ينبغي أن تُعامل بشكل أفضل من الناس الذين نجحوا.
It's called smart failure. Why? Because you can't put it on your C.V.
يطلق عليه الفشل الذكي. لماذا؟ لأنه لا يمكن وضعه في السيرة الذاتية الخاصة بك
So what I want to leave you, then, is with the explanation
لذا ما أريد أن اتركه لكم، ثم، مع الشرح
of why I actually traveled 60,000 miles from my desk.
لماذا فعلا سافرت 60,000 كم انطلاقا من مكتبي.
When I realized the power of this new world,
عندما أدركت قوة هذا العالم الجديد،
I quit my safe teaching job, and set up a virtual business school,
إستقلت من وظيفتي التعليمية ، وأنشأت مدرسة أعمال افتراضية،
the first in the world, in order to teach people how to make this happen,
الأولى في العالم، من أجل تعليم الناس الكيفية التي تمكنهم من جعل ذلك يحدث،
and I used some of my learnings about some of the rules which I'd learned on myself.
ولقد استخدمت بعضا من معارفي حول بعض القواعد التي تعلمتها من نفسي.
If you're interested, worldaftermidnight.com, you'll find out more,
إذا كنت مهتما، worldaftermidnight.com ، ستجد المزيد من المعلومات،
but I've applied them to myself for over a decade,
كنت قد طبقتها على نفسي لأكثر من عقد،
and I'm still here, and I still have my house, and the most important thing is,
وأنا ما زلت هنا، وأنا لا أزال أملك منزلي، وأهم شيء هو،
I hope I've done enough to inject a little green ink into your lives,
أملي في أن أكون قد فعلت ما يكفي لضخ الحبرالأخضر قليلاً في حياتكم،
so that when you go away and you're making your next
حيث عندما تذهببون بعيداً وتصنعون
absolutely sensible and rational decision, you'll take some time to think,
قرارا القادم المعقول والحكيم ، فغنكم سوف تستغرقون بعضا من الوقت باعتقادي،
"Hmm, I wonder whether this also makes sense
"همم، أتعجّب إن كان لهذا معنى حقا
in our new world after midnight." Thank you very much.
في عالمنا بعد منتصف الليل." شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you, thank you. (Applause)
شكراً لكم، شكراً لكم. (تصفيق)